Mss.B.M781 Mss.B.M781
American Philosophical Society
Autograph collection, 1816-1917
Mss.B.M781
American Philosophical Society
0.5 Linear feet
There are 153 letters in this collection, many addressed to Aubrey Lackington Moore, an English writer who tried to reconcile evolution and traditional Christianity. Some letters discuss scientific questions of the day, while others are formal social notes. Also includes 24 clipped signatures, inlcuding those of Sir Henry Wentworth Acland; Goerge Bentham; H. A. Bruce; S. H. Butcher; Matthewss Duncan; Percy Gardner; George Gritchett; G. Grote; Alfred Cort Haddon; Sir Prescott Gardner Hewitt; William Guyer Hunter; Thomas Henry Huxley; John Lingard; Thomas Babington Macauley; Miss K. Aubrey Moore; Louis Pasteur; Sir John Russell Reynolds, bart.; Thomas Smith; James Leigh Strachan-Davidson; Agnes Strickland; and Arthur Thomason.
177 items.
Moore, E. M.,collector.
Box 1
Early American History Note
The Moore Autograph Collection contains a series of individual letters that E.M. Morre collected in the twentieth century. The letters are primarily from British thinkers written in the nineteenth century, especially the 1880s and 1890s.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Purchased from Fleming (Sotheby, nos. 229 and 232; $150.76) and accessioned, 1961 (1961 1440ms).
Abernethy, John, 1764-1831; Acland, Henry W., (Henry Wentworth), 1815-1900; Adams, John Couch, 1819-1892; Bentham, George, 1800-1884; Blackwell, Elizabeth, 1821-1910; Brown-Séquard, Charles-Edouard, 1817-1894; Darwin, Francis, Sir, 1848-1925; Fletcher, C. R. L., (Charles Robert Leslie), 1857-1934; Flower, William Henry, 1831-1899; Galton, Francis, Sir, 1822-1911; Gladstone, W. E., (William Ewart), 1809-1898; Grote, George, 1794-1871; Hooker, William Jackson, Sir, 1785-1865; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895; Lecky, William Edward Hartpole, 1838-1903; Lodge, Oliver, Sir, 1851-1940; Lubbock, J. W., (John William), 1803-1865; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892; Paget, James, Sir, 1814-1899; Pasteur, Louis, 1822-1895; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894; Thomson, William; Trevelyan, George Otto, Sir, 1838-1928; Turner, William, Sir; Virchow, Rudolf Ludwig Karl, 1821-1902; Wallace, Alfred Russel, 1823-1913; Autographs.; Beyond Early America; Evolution.; Miscellaneous; Science.
- Autograph collection, Moore, E.M.
  Scope and Contents note
  D. 153 items (letters and documents) and 24 autographs (clipped from letters, etc). Various sizes. Many of these pertain directly to Aubrey Lackington Moore, Who attempted to reconcile the evolution-religion controversy. Table of contents available.
  - Letter to Richard Shute, August 2, 1816; Rennie, John
    A.L.S. 1 p.
  - Letter to F. Paget, Sept. 11, 1827; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Manby, George William, 1765-1854
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Moore collection.) Resigns from the Yarmouth Cricket Club.
  - Letter to Thomas Hamlet, March 19, 1829; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Laurie, Peter, Sir, 1778-1861
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Recommends a friend for a position in Marylebone hospital.
  - Letter to George Lackington, March 20, 1829; 9-3/4x8; Haines, John
    Hampstead, A.L.S. 3p.and add.with end.by Astlee Cooper. (see Moore autograph collection.) Illness of a child and the diagnosis.
  - Note to Miss Lackington, Nov. 25, 1836; 6x4-1/4; Cooper, Astley, Sir, 1768-1841
    A.N.in 3rd.P. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Pays his respects.
  - Letter to Mr. Gandar, May 2, 1840; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Stanhope, Philip Henry Stanhope, Earl, 1805-1875
    L.in 3rd.P. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) States number of proof portraits is different from number on the bill.
  - Letter to Mrs. Lackington, Feb. 24, 1843; 4-1/2x3-3/4; Turner, Sharon, 1768-1847
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Asks that a name be inserted in a list "for the blind."
  - Letter to D[aniel] Moore, Feb. 22, 1847; 7x4-1/2; Howe, Richard William Penn Curzon-Howe, Earl, 1796-1870
    Cassiobury, A.L.in 3rd.P. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Queen Adelaide thanks him for his publication.
  - Letter to D[aniel] Moore, Dec. 11, 1848; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Wellington, Arthur Wellesley, Duke of, 1769-1852
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Has returned all the papers and considers the matter closed.
  - Letter to Daniel Moore, Dec. 13, 1848; 7x4-3/4; Wellington, Arthur Wellesley, Duke of, 1769-1852
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Sends enclosed for Rev. Moore "to apply it if he thinks prpper."
  - Letter to D[aniel] Moore, Dec. 21, 1854; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Gleig, George Robert, 1796-1888
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for manual for camps for the Crimean War.
  - Letter to [Sir] James Paget, [bart], June 27, 1856; 7x4-1/2; Royal Society (Great Britain)
    A.L.S.: W.Sharpey. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) He is to deliver the Croonian lecture for the ensuing year.
  - Letter to D[aniel] Moore, Aug. 24, 1859; 7x4-1/2; Gladstone, W. E. (William Ewart), 1809-1898
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Explains why an appointment was filled the way it was. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to ----, March 8, 1864; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Nasmyth, James, 1808-1890
    Kent, A.L.S. 1p. Mutilated. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for publication on tension of thick cylinders.
  - Letter to Mrs. Paget, May 15, 1864; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Hooker, William Jackson, Sir, 1785-1865
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Forwards plants and describes changes in the gardens at Kew.
  - Letter to Daniel Moore, March 30, 1866; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Sydney,
    L. 3p.and add. (see Moore autograph collection.) Appoints him honorary chaplain to the queen.
  - Letter to Rev. W. W. Cazalet, July 4, 1867; 7x4-1/2; Thompson, Henry, Sir, 1820-1904
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Col. Wilkins, July 7, 1868; 7x4-1/2; Rassam, Hormuzd, 1826-1910
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Moore autograph collection.) Cannot accept his invitation, but will try to see him later.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget,[bart.], Feb. 26, 1869; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Watson, Thomas, Sir, 1792-1882
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Congratulations on his son's success.
  - Letter to [Sir] James Paget, bart., June 28, 1869; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Watson, Thomas, Sir, 1792-1882
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Moore autograph collection.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to "My dear Katie;", Sept. 29, 1869; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Acland, Henry W. (Henry Wentworth), 1815-1900
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Sends sketch.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, bart., Oct. 14, 1869; 7x4-1/2; Leopold, Prince, Duke of Albany, 1853-1884
    Balmoral, A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for autographs. Friendly letter
  - Letter to D[aniel] Moore, Oct. 23, 1869; 7x4-1/2; Gladstone, W. E. (William Ewart), 1809-1898
    Chester, A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Has read of his appointment to a committee.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget, bart.], Oct. 3, 1871; 7x4-1/2; Beresford Hope, A. J. B. (Alexander James Beresford), 1820-1887
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Hopes he will be at a meeting of the London University.
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore, Dec. 24, 1871; 7x4-1/2; Burrows, Ronald Montagu
    Oxford, A.L.S. 4p.,end. (see Moore autograph collection.) States he passed his examinations. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Lady Paget, Jan. 4, 1872; 6-1/4x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p.and end. (see Moore autograph collection.) Will be happy to see her at 3 P.M.
  - Letter to Miss Paget, Feb. 8, 1872; 7x4-1/2; Parkes, Edmund A. (Edmund Alexander), 1819-1876
    Southampton, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Accepts invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to Lady Paget, July 8, 1872; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Gross, Samuel D. (Samuel David), 1805-1884
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for the favors bestowed on him.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], bart., July 29, 1872; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Corrigan, Dominic, Sir, 1802-1880
    London, A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Cannot accept invitation to dinner due to an attack of the gout.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget, bart.], Jan. 31, 1873; 11x4-1/2; Kennedy, Thomas F. (Thomas Francis), 1788-1879
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Returns article with no comment to add. Is getting better slowly; Sorry he could not attend Adam Sedgwick's funeral.
  - Letter to Mrs. Eaton, Dec. 30, 1874; 6x4; Watson, Thomas, Sir, 1792-1882
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Prescribes for illness.
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore, March 23, 1877; 7x4-1/2; Gull, William Withey, Sir, 1816-1890
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Prescribes regimen for him.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, June 13, 1880; 7X4-1/2; Frankland, Edward, Sir, 1825-1899
    [bart.] A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Will analyze the water.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, bart., May 7, 1881; 7x4-1/2; Currie, Edmund Hay
    London, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for seeing him.
  - Letter to ----, Jan. 12, 1882; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Spottiswoode, William, 1825-1883
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Sends in notes on what he will say at the meeting.
  - Letter to Miss Gladstone, March 29, 1883; 7x4-1/2; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Appreciates the list, and if he doesn't hear from her to the contrary will forward a copy to Grant Duff.
  - Letter to Lady Sophia Palmer, Aug. 20, 1883; 7x4-1/2; Trevelyan, George Otto, Sir, 1838-1938
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Suggests alternate days for dinner.
  - Letter to ----, Sept. 16, 1883; 10-1/2x8; Bonney, T. G. (Thomas George), 1833-1923
    Southport, England, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Subscribes for portrait of Burdon-San-derson.
  - Letter to Miss Gladstone, Oct. 11, 1883; 7x4-1/2; Trevelyan, George Otto, Sir, 1838-1938
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Returns letter.
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore, Dec. 2, 1883; 7x4-1/2; Paget, James, Sir, 1814-1899
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for his publication. Refers to Huxley and to Burdon-Sanderson.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Catharine Hunt] Moore, May 16, 1884; 6x4; Sayce, A. H. (Archibald Henry), 1845-1933
    Oxford, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Accepts invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to ----, June 16, 1884; 7-1/2x4-1/2; McCarthy, Justin H. (Justin Huntly), 1860-1936
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for congratulations.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Eleanor Gutch] Freeman, Oxford, March 24, 1885; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Freeman, Edward Augustus, 1823-1892
    Périgueax, A.L.S.with initials. on postal card. 1p. and add. (see Moore autograph collection.) Is travelling and utterly spent.
  - Letter to Aubrey [Lackington] Moore, Nov. 19, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Halifax, Charles Lindley Wood, Viscount, 1839-1934
    Exeter, A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for paper.
  - Letter to Aubrey [Lackington] Moore, Dec. 10, 1885; 7-1/2x5; Gladstone, W. E. (William Ewart), 1809-1898
    Chester, A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Defines evolution.
  - Letter to Aubrey [Lackington] Moore, Dec. 27, 1885; 7-1/2x4-3/4; Gladstone, W. E. (William Ewart), 1809-1898
    Chester, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Moore autograph collection.) Concerning his dispute with Huxley on religion and evolution. Refers to Asa Gray and Sir Henry Wentworth Acland.
  - Proem to Genesis: A plea for a fair trial, Jan., 1886; 10x6; Gladstone, W. E. (William Ewart), 1809-1898
    Printed D.addressed to Rev. Aubrey Moore. 22p.end.by W.E.G[ladstone]. (see Moore autograph collection.) Concerning Huxley, evolution, etc.
  - Letter to Madame Douglas Murray, London, July 2, 1886; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Lesseps, Ferdinand de, 1805-1894
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Moore autograph collection) Arrives in London Saturday and hopes to see them.
  - Letter to Sir George Paget, Jan., 1887; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Adams, John Couch, 1819-1892
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Will join the family for the jubilee.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, bart., April 7, 1887; 6-1/2x4-1/4; Newton, C. T. (Charles Thomas), 1816-1894
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Will send titles "of the best authorities on the Tanagra statuettes."
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore, May 7, 1887; 6x4; Wakeman, Henry Offley, 1852-1899
    Oxford, A.L.S.with initials. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Congratulates him on the honor he has received.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, Dec. 14, 1887; Richardson, Benjamin Ward, Sir
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore, Feb. 16, [1888]; 7x4-1/2; Lankaster, E. Ray (Edwin Ray), Sir, 1847-1929
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Concerning his pamphlet on Darwin and Religion.
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore, Feb. 19, 1888; 7-3/4x5; Flower, William Henry, 1831-1899
    London, A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Concerning his lecture on evolution and the reaction of the London clergy.
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore, Feb. 21, 1888; Paget, James, Sir, 1814-1899
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore, Feb. 23, 1888; Flower,William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington] Moore, Feb. 27, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Flower, William Henry, 1831-1899
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for the publication on evolution which he ought to send to Huxley.
  - Letter to Miss Paget, March 3, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Praises photography. Asks for admission to hear Sir James speak.
  - Letter to ----, March 10, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Ollier, M.
    L.S. 3p. In French. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for publication on cancer.
  - Letter to Rev. A[ubrey] L[ackington] Moore, March 15, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895
    A.L.S. 8p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Biblical vs.Darwin's"origin."
  - Letter to Miss Paget, March 23, 1888; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Brown-Séquard, Charles Edouard, 1817-1894
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Forwards letter for her collection.
  - Letter to Aubrey [Lackington] Moore, April 8, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Halifax, Charles Lindley Wood, Viscount, 1839-1934
    Doncaster, A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Enjoyed his sermon.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, bart., May 6, 1888; 8x5; Billings, John S. (John Shaw), 1838-1913
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Asks information for medical museum. Refers to Sir Henry Acland.
  - Letter to Aubrey [Lackington] Moore, Oxford, July 22, 1888; 4-3/4x3; Gladstone, W. E. (William Ewart), 1809-1898
    A.L.S.with initials on postal card. 1p. and add. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for articles on evolution sent him.
  - Letter to [Aubrey Lackington Moore], Nov. 29, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Gairdner, James, 1828-1912
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Cannot remember, at this time, where a phrase he quotes came from.
  - Letter to Aubrey L[ackington] Moore, Jan. 24, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Gairdner, James, 1828-1912
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Concerning a phrase used in one of publications.
  - Letter to Miss Aubrey Moore, May 4, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Fisher, H. A. L. (Herbert Albert Laurens), 1865-1940
    Oxford, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Permits her to sketch the garden.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, [bart.], Jan. 18, 1890; 7x4-1/2; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Death of Moore.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Catherine Hunt] Moore, Feb. 28, [1890]; 7x4-1/2; Wakeman, Henry Offley, 1852-1899
    Delhi, A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Sorrows at the death of her husband.
  - Letter to "Lady Sophie", Feb. 26, 1890; 7x4-1/2; Lecky, William Edward Hartpole, 1838-1903
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Will visit her tomorrow.
  - Letter to W. Lock, March 20, 1890; 7x4-1/2; Balfour, Arthur James Balfour, Earl of, 1848-1930
    Typed L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Contributes toward the Aubrey Lackington Moore memorial.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget, bart.], May 30, 1890; 8x5; Baden-Powell, George, 1847-1898
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Glad to hear of his efforts for an organization (Toronto University Library?) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, bart., June 27, 1890; 7x4-1/2; Grant Duff, Mountstuart E. (Mountstuart Elphinstone), Sir, 1829-1906
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Looks forward to seeing him and family.
  - Letter to Miss Moore, Oct. 31, [1890]; 5-1/4x3-1/2; Bright, W.
    Oxford, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Moore autograph collection.) Is busy and may not be able to visit.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Catharine Hunt] Moore, Dec. 10, [1890?]; 7x4-1/2; Fletcher, C. R. L. (Charles Robert Leslie), 1857-1934
    Oxford, A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Sends news of his new appointment. Forwards book of flowers for gift.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, Jan. 20, 1891; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895
    A.L.S. 2 p.
  - Letter to ----, June 6, 1891; 7x4-1/2; Kitchin, G. W. (George William), 1827-1912
    Oxford, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for the invitation to the meeting.
  - Letter to Mr. Moore, Oct. 26, 1891; 7x4-1/4; Paget, James, Sir, 1814-1899
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Hopes his son will work as he should at Oxford.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget, bart.], Oct. 31, 1891; 6x4; Bramwell, George William Wilshere Bramwell, Baron, 1808-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Congratulates him on his son's appointment.
  - Letter to ----, Dec. 31, 1891; 7x4-1/2; Lavet, P.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Moore autograph collection.) Wishes her a happy new year and hopes she will suffer less.
  - Letter to Lock: Monday., [1891]; 6x4; Fowler, W. Warde (William Warde), 1847-1921
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Concerning Aubrey Lackington Moore.
  - Letter to "My dear Mary" [Paget?], Feb. 19, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Paget, James, Sir, 1814-1899
    London, A.L.S. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Hopes their holiday is doing them good. Sends money.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, bart., May 1, 1892; 6x4; Judd, John W. (John Wesley), 1840-1916
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Encloses paper with signatures of those at the Philosophical Club dinner.
  - Letter to Miss Paget, June 14, 1892; 6x3-3/4; Horsley, Victor, Sir, 1857-1916
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thinks the ought to be admission into the hospital at once.
  - Letter to Miss Goodrich-Freer, Jan. 19, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Royal Botanic Garden, Edinburgh
    London, A.L.S: Isaac Bayley Balfour. 3p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Can suggest names for lecturers, if she will state salary.
  - Letter to W[illiam] T[homas] Stead, June 23, 1893; 13-1/4x8; Kelvin, William Thomson, Baron, 1824-1907
    Glasgow, L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Believes "nearly everything in hypnotism and clairvoyance is imposture, and the rest bad observation."
  - The study of psychical and occult phenomena, July 12, 1893; 9x7; Braddon, Edward, Sir, 1829-1904
    A.D.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.)
  - Letter to [William Thomas] Stead, July 16, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895
    A.L.S. 4p.,end. (see Moore autograph collection.) His views of scientific inventigation coincide with Lankaster's.
  - Letter to Miss Freer, June 11, 1894; 9x7; Lodge, Oliver, Sir, 1851-1940
    Liverpool, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Is willing his letters should appear in her paper.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, [bart.], July 24, 1894; 7x4-1/2; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore collection of autographs.) Thinks King's College will not stand in the way, and their cause is safe.
  - Letter to Mr. Thompson, Nov. 29, 1894; 8x5; Rutherford, William G. (William Gunion), 1853-1907
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Forwards item and invites them to his home.
  - Letter to Miss Freer, Dec. 30, 1894; 9x7; Lodge, Oliver, Sir, 1851-1940
    Liverpool, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thinks she has written an article and wishes to thank her for it.
  - Letter to "Miss Mary;", Jan. 9, 1895; 8x5; Virchow, Rudolf Ludwig Karl, 1821-1902
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p.,end. In German. (see Moore autograph collection.) Sympathy on death of her mother and hopes she will be an aid to her father.
  - Letter to ----, June 3, 1895; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Ericksen, Sir John Eric, 1818-1896
    A.L. in 3rd.P. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Will attend meeting.
  - Letter to Miss Greer, June 5, 1895; 6x3-3/4; Horsley, Victor, Sir, 1857-1916
    (see Moore autograph collection.) Sorry not to have answered her sooner, but pressure of work would not permit.
  - Letter to Miss Freer, Aug. 3, 1895; 7x4-1/2; Besant, Annie, 1847-1933
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to Mrs. Freer, Aug. 8, 1896; 6x4; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
    Kent, A.LS. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Asks her to forward enclosure to E. Blackwell.
  - Letter to Miss Freer, Feb. 25, 1897; 6x4; Sieveking, Edward H. (Edward Henry), 1816-1904
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Congratulates her on success of her educational set-up.
  - Letter to Mrs. Thompson, June 14, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Thomson, J. J. (Joseph John), 1856-1940
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for forwarding letter.
  - Letter to ----, July 22, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Dixon, Richard Watson, 1833-1900
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Has written a review, but wants to check some items before forwarding it.
  - Letter to Mr. Poole, Nov. 11, 1897; 7-1/2x5-1/2; Acton, John Emerich Edward Dalberg Acton, Baron, 1834-1902
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Asks that the enclosed chapter be forwarded to his brother for "desired chap[ter]."
  - Letter to Mrs. Aubrey [Catharine Hunt] Moore, Dec. 8, 1897; 6x4; Evans, Arthur, Sir, 1851-1941
    A.D.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Invitation to brig the children for a New Year's Eve dinner and dance.
  - Letter to Miss Weld, Sept. 28, 1898; 7x4-1/4; Galton, Francis, Sir, 1822-1911
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Thanks for shipment of letter and fruit.
  - Letter to Dr. Lock, Oct. 14, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Puller, F. W. (Frederick William), 1843-1938
    Oxford, A.L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to Miss Goodrich, Jan. 19, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Galton, Francis, Sir, 1822-1911
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Concerning eugenics.
  - Letter to C. H. Firth, Oxford, Jan. 28, 1899; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Gardiner, Samuel Rawson, 1829-1902
    A.L.S.on postal card. 1p.and add. (see Moore autograph collection.) Has returned with publications.
  - Letter to Miss Paget, April 6, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Radstock, Granville Waldegrave, Baron, 1833-1913
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Will contribute as she requests. Asks of Sir James.
  - Letter to Mr. Douglas-Murray, June 12, 1899; 6-1/4x4; Crookes, William, 1832-1919
    London, Typed L.S. 1p. (see Moore autograph collection.) Will dine with him.
  - Letter to Miss Freer, Aug. 7, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Mitchell, Arthur, Sir, 1826-
    A.L.S. (see Moore autograph collection.) The cause and cure of hysteria as a disease. Spriitualism, etc.
  - Letter to Mr. Myres, Sept. 16, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Beddle, John, 1826-1911
    A.L.S. 2p.,end. (see Moore autograph collection. Concerning a paper which he would like to correct before publication.